[music]
John Kyriakou is a former
CIA agent and former senior investigator on the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee who notably served
23 months in prison as a result of
his efforts to oppose the
government's torture program.
In an article in an international media outlet, he
discusses at length what
Greeks expect from the election. He puts a rein on
our expectations,
stating, among other things, that I
spent the last two weeks on
my ancestral island of Rhodes in
Greece helping my cousin sort out his
father's lamb estate. It's no surprise
that everyone, literally
everyone, wanted to talk about
this month's U.S. presidential election. Greece has
long had an anti-American streak
stemming from the
U.S. support for the military
dictatorship of
1967-1974 who killed, tortured and
imprisoned thousands of people just
because of their political views
indeed the ruling conservative party
of the new democracy
only wins elections because there are so many
socialist and communist parties
that divide the left vote and
allow the conservatives to
govern but to my great surprise
every leftist I have
spoken to including almost everyone
in my family from the KK to the
socialist panhellenic socialist
movement PASOK offer full support
to donald trump after hearing it over and
over I decided to do some research to
understand how lifelong socialists and
communists can support
a billionaire businessman who
leads a capitalist and
conservative political party or do they
see trump as a
peacemaker the reasons for
their admiration for trump were quite simple
They saw Donald Trump as the
anti-war candidate. Greeks
know nothing about American
domestic politics and generally don't care. They
give you a blank stare when you
mention abortion or
healthcare or the environment, but they
care about war. They hate what's
happening to the Palestinians and the
Lebanese, despite the fact that
his government is unabashedly pro-
Israel, just like Donald Trump. They hate
that the United States armed an
Orthodox Christian country, Ukraine,
against another, Russia. They hate
that the United States has
done nothing about the 50-year Turkish
military occupation of Cyprus.
Thank you for following us to be the
first to receive all the latest
developments. Like and subscribe to
our channel.